

■ 513-535-1392 |
griffin.solimini@gmail.com |
griffin-solimini-25571062

Summary_

Software Engineer with 6 years industry experience in a broad range of areas including frontend user experiences, backend development, and application infrastructure. Motivated about problem solving in many spaces, but specifically interested and passionate about exploring areas of lower level development close to hardware.

Work Experience_

Microsoft - Xbox Game Pass Redmond, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2

Sept. 2019 - Present

- · Lead engineering partnerships with Electronic Arts and Ubisoft to design and implement custom app-to-app communication mechanisms used to expand the Game Pass catalog with third party gaming content. Utilized gRPC, Windows protocol handlers, and registry to implement these integration solutions.
- Improving the existing, ad-hoc, solutions: currently designing and implementing a COM-based, public-facing SDK to allow for more streamlined integration for past and future game catalog partners. Providing a contract to help third party publishers seamlessly integrate their content into the Xbox PC client with minimal additional Xbox engineering effort.
- Implemented both the frontend and backend of a new PC Game Pass upsell surface to be added into the Windows operating system's out-of-box experience, utilizing existing Microsoft infrastructure. Responsible for driving additional growth for the top-of-funnel PC subscriber count.
- · Increased robustness of Xbox PC client's infrastructure, leading to improvements in reliability, performance, and developer experience. Tasks included but not limited to: migrating the Xbox PC client to utilize the Hermes JavaScript engine, facilitating React Native Windows upgrades into the application, and onboarding the application to a new application monitoring platform (sentry.io).

Microsoft - Xbox Game Pass Redmond, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Nov. 2018 - Sept. 2019

- Built and owned the subscription page for the PC client, the surface within the app used to drive user acquisition and retention.
- Shipped numerous user facing features for the first version of the Xbox PC client, and features supporting the launch of PC Game Pass subscription.
- Investigated and fixed critical bugs in preparation for the launch of the Xbox PC client and PC Game Pass at E3 2019.

Microsoft - Silicon, Graphics, and Media

Redmond, WA

PROGRAM MANAGER

Sept. 2017 - Nov. 2018

- · Lead the team relationship with Qualcomm with a dev lead counterpart, tracked bugs and validation for incoming software, and managed code flow externally back to Qualcomm.
- · Kept work streams efficient and well documented to internal/external partners in order to develop and deliver a high quality product to our vertical teams

Personal and Skill Development Projects __

KEYBOARD PCB https://github.com/gryph6/keyboard

- Designed and built a PCB for a keyboard using an ATMEGA32u4 microcontroller.
- Supports 68 keys, a rotary encoder, an OLED display, and USB2 over a USBC port.
- Designed the schematics in KiCad, selected components, worked with PCBWay to fabricate and assemble the PCB, and utilized QMK framework to write and flash custom firmware.

CHIP-8 EMULATOR https://github.com/gryph6/Griff-8

- Building a CHIP-8 emulator in C++ (https://wikipedia.org/wiki/CHIP-8).
- · Implemented virtual memory, registry, stack, and 35 opcodes in order to build a working emulator utilizing Direct2D for graphics.
- Capable of passing a community ROM test, and can play several games.
- Next steps include adding support for more games, code cleanup, and adding SUPER-CHIP-8 opcode support.

Education

Ohio State University Columbus, OH

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug. 2013 - May 2017

• 3.93 GPA, Summa Cum Laude with Honors Distinction.

• Eminence Fellowship and Full Scholarship, given to recognize previous high academic performance.

GRIFFIN SOLIMINI AUGUST 6, 2023